<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marco&#39;s Nonsense</title>
    <link>https://blog.marco.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Marco&#39;s Nonsense</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 20:32:59 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.marco.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://blog.marco.io/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.marco.io/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Move static content to static Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like&#xA;▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png should become&#xA;▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>作业一 云服务器的基本使用</title>
      <link>https://blog.marco.io/posts/homework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 20:32:59 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.marco.io/posts/homework/</guid>
      <description>作业一 云服务器的基本使用&#xA;学号：21311162&#xA;姓名：伍开钰&#xA;Have a good day !&#xA;安装 Hugo 链接：https://gohugo.io/installation/linux/&#xA;Prerequisites Git Go 安装 # 使用 Go 安装 CGO_ENABLED=1 go install -tags extended github.com/gohugoio/hugo@latest # 配置 Go 的 bin 路径 echo &amp;#39;export PATH=$PATH:/pathto/go/bin&amp;#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.zshrc source ~/.zshrc # 查看 hugo 版本 hugo version Quick Start Create a site # 在 quickstart 目录中为您的项目创建目录结构。 hugo new site quickstart cd quickstart git init # 将 yinyang 主题克隆到 themes 目录中，并将其作为 Git 子模块添加到您的项目中。 git submodule add https://github.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>赤壁赋</title>
      <link>https://blog.marco.io/posts/cn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.marco.io/posts/cn/</guid>
      <description>原文 壬戌之秋，七月既望，蘇子與客泛舟遊於赤壁之下。清風徐來，水波不興。舉酒屬客，誦明月之詩，歌窈窕之章。少焉，月出於東山之上，徘徊於斗牛之間。白露橫江，水光接天。縱一葦之所如，凌萬頃之茫然。浩浩乎如馮虛御風，而不知其所止；飄飄乎如遺世獨立,羽化而登仙。&#xA;於是飲酒樂甚，扣舷而歌之。歌曰：“桂棹兮蘭槳，擊空明兮溯流光。渺渺兮予懷，望美人兮天一方。”客有吹洞簫者，倚歌而和之。其聲嗚嗚然，如怨如慕，如泣如訴；餘音嫋嫋，不絕如縷。舞幽壑之潛蛟，泣孤舟之嫠婦。&#xA;蘇子愀然，正襟危坐，而問客曰：“何爲其然也？”客曰：“‘月明星稀，烏鵲南飛。’此非曹孟德之詩乎？西望夏口，東望武昌，山川相繆，鬱乎蒼蒼，此非孟德之困於周郎者乎？方其破荊州，下江陵，順流而東也，舳艫千里，旌旗蔽空，釃酒臨江，橫槊賦詩，固一世之雄也，而今安在哉？況吾與子漁樵於江渚之上，侶魚蝦而友麋鹿，駕一葉之扁舟，舉匏樽以相屬。寄蜉蝣於天地，渺滄海之一粟。哀吾生之須臾，羨長 江之無窮。挾飛仙以遨遊，抱明月而長終。知不可乎驟得，託遺響於悲風。”&#xA;蘇子曰：“客亦知夫水與月乎？逝者如斯，而未嘗往也；盈虛者如彼，而卒莫消長也。蓋將自其變者而觀之，則天地曾不能以一瞬；自其不變者而觀之，則物與我皆無盡也，而又何羨乎！且夫天地之間，物各有主，苟非吾之所有，雖一毫而莫取。惟江上之清風，與山間之明月，耳得之而爲聲，目遇之而成色，取之無禁，用之不竭。是造物者之無盡藏也，而吾與子之所共適。”(共適 一作：共食) 客喜而笑，洗盞更酌。餚核既盡，杯盤狼籍。相與枕藉乎舟中，不知東方之既白。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://blog.marco.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.marco.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am an undergraduate student of the School of Software Engineering in the Sun Yat-sen University. Currently, I am conducting research under the guidance of Assistant Professor Jianguo Chen. Our research focuses on deep learning-based computer vision, more specifically, 3D point clouds. At the same time, I am involved in Professor Yuxin Su’s research group, where I am learning about topics related to operating systems and cloud computing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title>
      <link>https://blog.marco.io/posts/goisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.marco.io/posts/goisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Hugo uses the excellent Go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of similarities in Go templates.&#xA;This document is a brief primer on using Go templates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://blog.marco.io/posts/hugoisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.marco.io/posts/hugoisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Step 1. Install Hugo Go to Hugo releases and download the appropriate version for your OS and architecture.&#xA;Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.&#xA;More complete instructions are available at Install Hugo&#xA;Step 2. Build the Docs Hugo has its own example site which happens to also be the documentation site you are reading right now.&#xA;Follow the following steps:&#xA;Clone the Hugo repository Go into the repo Run hugo in server mode and build the docs Open your browser to http://localhost:1313 Corresponding pseudo commands:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
